Errol G. Markland Jr.

https://errolmarkland.com https://github.com/emarkland errol.markland@gmail.com | (347) 201-1580

Summary:

Web developer with an emphasis in back-end development working 5 years in a startup environment. Knowledgeable with all levels of web development cycle. Familiar with many programming languages including C# and Python. Able to quickly adapt to changing requirements and software roles.

Projects:

Article Tracker April 2015 - Present

- Tracks articles read around the web and posts results to a specified endpoint
- Currently supports Reddit and Hacker News
- Created using Python

Personal PHP ORM Dec 2014 - Present

- Rapidly generate consistent object models in PHP by reading database schema
- Currently only supports MySQL.

Experience:

appFigures 2012 - Present

Back-end Web Developer

- Built and maintained several internal software tools to increase productivity for other internal teams in C# and .NET
- Processed large datasets about public app data to gain new insights with Python and Docker. Automated with CRON.
- Increased service utility by adding support for 2 app stores, 11 ad networks, and an external backup service.
- Architected software library/tools to support partnership with Adobe Analytics.

QMedic Oct 2015 - Jun 2016

Contract Software Developer

- Used JavaScript to build a set of browser-based data visualization tools that adheres to the company's proprietary data formats
- Built a proof-of-concept Android app to assist with collecting health-related data

National Institute of Standards and Technology

May 2011 - August 2011

Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship at Information Technology Lab, Guest Researcher

■ Web Application Development for Computer Security Metadata

City College of New York

Louis Stokes Alliance for Minority Participation (LSAMP), Undergraduate Researcher

2010 - 2011

■ Mentor-guided research in the field of cryptography

Grove School of Engineering – Journal of Student Research, Web Developer

2010 - 2011

2009 - 2011

■ Implement the latest articles/magazines relating to research involving the Grove School of Engineering

Software Training Instructor

Teach software applications and languages from beginner to intermediate skill levels

- Assist people in troubleshooting their software-related concerns
- Earned Employee of the Month, April 2011

Education and Cerfications:

CompTIA Security+, Feb 2017

OSCP (Offensive Security Certified Professional), Feb 2017 - Current

City College of New York, Grove School of Engineering

New York, NY

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) in Computer Engineering

Fall 2011

Skills Inventory:

Languages: C#, Java, Python, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, C++ **Operating Systems:** Mac OS, Microsoft Windows XP/7/10, Ubuntu

Software: Visual Studio, SVN/Mercurial/Git, Redis, Memcached, Docker, Fiddler